A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Publications, SG 1, Series 13 FA285
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Publications, SG 1, Series 13
1936-1980
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund
FA285
61.2 Cubic Feet 139 boxes
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement note
This series has been divided into ten subseries:
Subseries 1 Annual Reports
Subseries 2 Authors
Subseries 3 Book Program
Subseries 4 Harvard Press Reports
Subseries 5 Old Book Program - Authors Files
Subseries 6 Out-of-Print Publications
Subseries 7 Publications (Adm-h Files)
Subseries 8 Reviews
Subseries 9 Titles
Subseries 10 Miscellaneous
Subseries 11 Authors' Files
These subseries reflect the administration created by the Division of Publications.
Biographical/Historical note
The Commonwealth Fund was established in 1918 with an endowment of $10 million from Mrs. Stephen V. Harkness for "benevolent, religious, educational and like purposes." The early grants supported a variety of programs while generally promoting welfare, especially child welfare. Several grants were made in the field of medical research, but the Board of Directors decided in 1920 that this field was already sufficiently supported by other philanthropic organizations.
Despite this decision, by the mid-1920s the chief interest of the Fund had become public health, including mental hygiene, community health, rural hospitals, medical research, and medical education. Other grant areas included war relief, educational and legal research, child welfare, and international medical fellowships.
File Plan note
Former Classification: IX; IV 4B 4
Scope and Contents note
The Commonwealth Fund's Division of Publications series is concerned with the publishing of books, journals, articles, and pamphlets. This series consists of correspondence, reports, financial papers, and a few pamphlets and books. The documents are mostly concerned with the financing and publishing of books, and the relationship of the Division with the authors and publishing companies.
Other Finding Aids
Other available finding aids describing the Commonwealth Fund records include:
FA247 Commonwealth Fund Harkness House drawings
FA276 Commonwealth Fund records, Annual Reports, SG 1, Series 4
FA277 Commonwealth Fund records, Archives/Library, SG 1, Series 5
FA278 Commonwealth Fund records, Austrian Program, SG 1, Series 6
FA279 Commonwealth Fund records, Board of Directors, SG 1, Series 7
FA280 Commonwealth Fund records, Capital Grants, SG 1, Series 8
FA281 Commonwealth Fund records, Child Health Demonstrations, SG 1, Series 9
FA282 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Community Clinics, SG 1, Series 10
FA283 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Health Studies, SG 1, Series 11
FA284 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Public Health, SG 1, Series 12
FA285 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Publications, SG 1, Series 13
FA286 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Rural Hospitals, SG 1, Series 14
FA287 Commonwealth Fund records, Educational Research, SG 1, Series 15
FA288 Commonwealth Fund records, English Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 16
FA289 Commonwealth Fund records, Finance Committee, SG 1, Series 17
FA290 Commonwealth Fund records, Grants, SG 1, Series 18
FA291 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Family, SG 1, Series 19
FA292 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, SG 1, Series 20
FA428 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, Fellows Reports, SG 1, Series 20A
FA293 Commonwealth Fund records, Institute for Child Guidance, SG 1, Series 21
FA294 Commonwealth Fund records, Interface Program, SG 1, Series 22
FA295 Commonwealth Fund records, Legal Research Program, SG 1, Series 23
FA296 Commonwealth Fund records, Living at Home Program, SG 1, Series 24
FA297 Commonwealth Fund records, Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 25
FA298 Commonwealth Fund records, Miscellaneous - unprocessed
FA299 Commonwealth Fund records, Personnel - unprocessed
FA300 Commonwealth Fund records, Pilgrim Trust, SG 1, Series 28
FA301 Commonwealth Fund records, Program for the Prevention of Delinquency, SG 1, Series 29
FA302 Commonwealth Fund records, Reference Files, SG 1, Series 30
FA303 Commonwealth Fund records, Reports of the General Director, SG 1, Series 31
FA304 Commonwealth Fund records, Treasurer, SG 1, Series 32
FA305 Commonwealth Fund records, Turndown Lists, SG 1, Series 33 - unprocessed
FA306 Commonwealth Fund records, Vertical File (R. Fitz), SG 1, Series 34 - unprocessed
FA307 Commonwealth Fund records, Visual Materials, SG 1, Series 35
FA389 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Historical Files, SG 1, Series 1
FA390 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Officers Files, SG 1, Series 2
FA429 Commonwealth Fund records, President, Margaret E. Mahoney, SG 2, Series 1
FA430 Commonwealth Fund records, Book Program, SG 2, Series 2
War relief; United States; New York (State); New York (N.Y.); Public welfare; Public health; Child welfare; Education, Rural; Child mental health; Child psychology; Medical research; Medical education; Medicine -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Medicine, Rural; Law; Hygiene; Legal research; Legal issues; Mental health; Harkness, Edward Stephen; Phillips Exeter Academy; Columbia University; Harvard University; Harkness, Charles W.; Social Science Research Council; Harkness, Mary Emma Stillman; Yale University; Harkness, Anna M. Richardson
- Annual Reports, 1
  Scope and Contents note
  This subseries consists of the Divisions' yearly reports. The reports are concerned with the publishing and selling of books from 1936 to 1965.
  - Annual Reports, 1936-1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1936-1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports, 1936-1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual Reports, 1936-1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Annual Reports, 1936-1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual Reports, 1936-1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Annual Reports, 1936-1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Annual Reports, 1949-1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Annual Reports, 1949-1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Annual Reports, 1949-1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Annual Reports, 1949-1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Authors, 2
  Arrangement note
  The folders are arranged alphabetically by author.
  The second subseries consists mostly of correspondence and a few pamphlets. This subseries is mostly concerned with the authors' writing and publishing of their books. The documents date from the late 1960s to the early 1980s.
  - Allen, J. Garrott - "The Epidemiology of Posttransfusions Hepatitis", July 9, 1971-September 29, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Allen, J. Garrott - "The National Blood Policy and its Implication", May 16, 1977-August 6, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Allen, J. Garrott - "The National Blood Policy and its Implication", May 16, 1977-August 6, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Altschulem, Mark - "Major Aspects of Pineal Physiology" [Grant-in-Aid], December 19, 1970-November 19, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Ambrose, Charles T. and Allan Donner - "Hemagglutination Assay in Immune Response", December 3, 1970-March 14, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences - "Survey of Sources for the History of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology", May 9, 1978-December 19, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Anlyan, William G. - "Future of Medical Education", January 5, 1971-November 15, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Anlyan, William G. - "Future of Medical Education", January 15, 1971-November 15, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Anlyan, William G., Kenneth Crispell and Barnes Woodhall - "Medical Center Administration Past, Present and Future", March 17, 1971-September 8, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Anlyan, William G., Kenneth Crispell and Barnes Woodhall - "Medical Center Administration Past, Present and Future", March 17, 1971-September 8, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Anlyan, William G., Kenneth Crispell and Barnes Woodhall - "Medical Center Administration Past, Present and Future", March 17, 1971-September 8, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Association of American Medical Colleges - "H.M.O. Workshop", September 15, 1972-May 16, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Association of Research Libraries - "Thirteen Colonial Americana" (Edward C. Latham), 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Beck, Ann - "History of the British Medical Administration of East Africa, 1900 to 1950", December 31, 1968-February 25, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Beecher, Henry K. - "Medicine at Harvard; A History of Ideas and their Influence on American Medicine", February 3, 1970-October 27, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Bonner, John T. - "Basic Problems in Emerging Science of Growth and Development", December 14, 1970-September 11, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Bowers, John Z. - "Rise of Western Medicine in Japan", June 23, 1967-December 2, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Brody, Eugene B. - "Social Forces and Mental Illness in Rio de Janeiro", June 12, 1967-December 10, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Brody, Eugene B. - "Social Forces and Mental Illness in Rio de Janeiro", June 12, 1967-December 10, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Callahan, Daniel - "Freedom, Coercion and Life Sciences" [Grant-in-Aid], July 8, 1969-February 9, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Callahan, Daniel - "Freedom, Coercion and Life Sciences" [Grant-in-Aid], July 8, 1969-February 9, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Callahan, Daniel - "Freedom, Coercion and Life Sciences" [Grant-in-Aid], July 8, 1969-February 9, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Callahan, Daniel - "Freedom, Coercion and Life Sciences" [Grant-in-Aid], July 8, 1969-February 9, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Callahan, Daniel - "Freedom, Coercion and Life Sciences" [Grant-in-Aid], July 8, 1969-February 9, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Center for Blood Research - "Chemistry and Physiology of the Human Plasma Proteins", December 30, 1977-October 29, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Chapman, Carleton B. - "Bibliography of Physical Exercise, 1500-1964", June 2, 1972-August 3, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Chapman, Carleton B. - "Bibliography of Physical Exercise, 1500-1964", June 2, 1972-August 3, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Chapman, Carleton B. - "Bibliography of Physical Exercise, 1500-1964", June 2, 1972-August 3, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Cline, Martin J. - "The White Cell", December 3, 1971-May 14, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - "Comprehensive Medical Care and Teaching" - (George G. Reader and Mary E. W. Goss) [Grant-in-Aid], January 18, 1965-February 16, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Cooper, Gale and Albert Schiller - "Anatomy of the Guinea Pig" [Grant-in-Aid], March 9, 1970-September 11, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Corsa, Leslie Jr. and Deborah Oakley - Population Planning Monograph, April 13, 1971-September 14, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Coser, Rose Laub, February 24, 1969-February 15, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Curran, William J. - "Interprofessional Training and Practice in Law and Medicine" [Grant-in-Aid], May 14, 1969-March 3, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Curran, William J. - "Interprofessional Training and Practice in Law and Medicine" [Grant-in-Aid], May 14, 1969-March 3, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Dawber, Thomas R. - "The Epidemiology of Atherosclerotic Disease", August 27, 1975-February 26, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Deikman, Arthur J. - "Western Psychiatry and Eastern Spiritual Traditions", November 8, 1976-June 15, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Dethier, Vincent G. - "Physiology and Behavior of the Blowfly", March 13, 1972-January 19, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Donabedian, Avedis - "Aspects of Medical Care Administration" [Grant-in-Aid], December 16, 1968-May 28, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Donabedian, Avedis - "Aspects of Medical Care Administration" [Grant-in-Aid], December 16, 1968-May 28, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Donabedian, Avedis - "Quality Assessment and Monitoring", September 26, 1978-October 20, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Dowling, Harry and Morton D. Bogdonoff - "Progress of Infectious Diseases in the 20th Century", October 9, 1973-February 3, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Dowling, Harry and Morton D. Bogdonoff - "Progress of Infectious Diseases in the 20th Century", October 9, 1973-February 3, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology - "Human Health and Disease", August 27, 1976-November 17, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Fink, B. Raymond and Robert J. Demarest - "Laryngeal Biomechanics", November 4, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Fishman, Robert A. - "Cerebrospinal Fluid: Physiological, Chemical and Clinical Aspects", December 8, 1977-August 13, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - "Freedom Hospital" (Documentary History and Drama", December 13, 1966-March 3, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Freymann, John Gordon [Grant-in-Aid], December 4, 1969-December 30, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Freymann, John Gordon [Grant-in-Aid], December 4, 1969-December 30, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Friedlaender, Jonathan S. - "Human Genetics and Society", February 3, 1976-November 1, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Gersh, Isidore - "Submicroscopic Cytochemistry" [Grant-in-Aid], February 21, 1963-October 29, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Gertler, Menard M. and Paul Dudley White - "Coronary Health Disease in Young Adults", December 24, 1969-February 26, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Gil, David George - "Violence Against Children: Physical Abuse in the United States", September 23, 1969-September 11, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Glaser, Gilbert H. - "Temporal Lobe (Psychomotor) Epilepsy: A Dynamic Approach", October 2, 1974-February 17, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Glaser, Robert J. - "Clinical Teaching and Health Systems" (Stanford Medical Facilities Planning Group), August 6, 1969-July 1, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Goldwater, Leonard J. [Grant-in-Aid], January 31, 1967-September 11, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Goldwater, Leonard J. [Grant-in-Aid], January 31, 1967-September 11, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Grob, Gerald N. - "Report on Insanity and Idiocy in Massachusetts" (Jarvis Report), December 9, 1966-November 19, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Grob, Gerald N. - "Report on Insanity and Idiocy in Massachusetts" (Jarvis Report), December 9, 1966-November 19, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Hale, Nathan George, Jr. - "James Jackson Putnam and Psychoanalysis: Letters Between Putnam and Sigmund Freud", February 2, 1971-April 3, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Ham, Thomas Hale - "The Student as a Colleague in Learning", December 11, 1973-September 11, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Harvard University (John F. Kennedy School of Government) - "Proceedings of the Conference on Regulation as an Instrument of Public Administration", March 16, 1977-January 23, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - Harvey, A. McGehee - "Evolution of Clinical Science in the United States", February 10, 1975-August 4, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Harwood, Alan - "A Handbook of Ethicity and Medical Care", April 22, 1977-June 20, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Heffron, Roderick and Benjamin White - "The Biology of the Pneumococcus Pneumonia, with Special Reference to Pneumococcus Labor Pneumonia", November 9, 1977-January 25, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 76)
  - Hirshfield, Daniel S. - "The Lost Reform: The Campaign for Compulsory Health Insurance in the United States from 1932 to 1943", August 23, 1968-June 2, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Holmes, Frederic Lawrence - "Claude Bernard and Animal Chemistry", October 8, 1971-January 2, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - House, William F. - "Ear Research Institute", October 10, 1979-August 2, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Hume, Michael - "Venous Thrombosis and Pulmonary Embolism", April 26, 1966-January 25, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - Hunterdon Medical Center (Robert R. Henderson), July 29, 1965-October 27, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - Jacobson, Harold G. - "The Radiology Skeletal Disorders", April 2, 1974-June 24, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Jarcho, Saul - "Development of the Concept of Heart Failures", January 11, 1979-November 12, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - Joint Committee for the Study of Education for Public Health, January 10, 1966-January 30, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Jordan, William S., Jr. - "Community Medicine in the United Kingdom", January 8, 1975-September 18, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Kean, B. H. - "Classics in Tropical Medicine", November 29, 1973-August 14, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Keys, Ancel - "Seven Countries: Death and Coronary Heart Disease", April 21, 1978-March 1, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Klausner, Samuel Z. [Grant-in-Aid], March 20, 1967-March 21, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Kosa, John, Aaron Antonvsky and Irving Zola - "Poverty and Health: A Sociological View", June 11, 1968-September 11, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - Lane, Roger - "Violent Death in the City", August 8, 1977-March 8, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 90)
  - Lee, Philip R. and Milton Silverman - "Pills, Profit and Politics" [Grant-in-Aid], February 3, 1970-May 22, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 91)
  - Lindheim, Roslyn and Helen H. Glaser - "Changing Hospital Environments for Children", December 9, 1969-September 21, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 92)
  - Lindheim, Roslyn and Helen H. Glaser - "Changing Hospital Environments for Children", December 9, 1969-September 21, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - Littlefield, John W. and Frank Ruddle - "Variation, Senescence and Neoplasia in Cultured Comatic Cell", April 19, 1972-april 9, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 94)
  - Loomis, Ted A. - "Biological Methods in Toxicology" [Grant-in-Aid], September 25, 1968-February 26, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 95)
  - Ludwig, Alfred O., Somers H. Sturgis and Benjamin Murawski - "Psychoanalytic and Psychophysiological Investigation in Gynecologic Disorders: An Attempt at Psycho-endocrine Correlations", April 3, 1958-August 29, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 96)
  - Lyden, Fremont, H. Jack Geiger and Osler L. Peterson - "The Training of Good Physicians: Critical Factors in Career Choices", January 30, 1968-October 30, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - Majno, Gujido - "Wounds and Inflamation: The Healing Hands" [Grant-in-Aid], May 25, 1966-December 21, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 98)
  - Majno, Gujido - "Wounds and Inflamation: The Healing Hands" [Grant-in-Aid], May 25, 1966-December 21, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 99)
  - Majno, Guido - "Wounds and Inflamation: The Healing Hands", January 3, 1974-June 14, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 100)
  - Margulies, Harold - "Foreign Medical Graduates in the United States", August 25, 1967-March 27, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 101)
  - Mark, Vernon H. and Frank Ervin - "The Correlation of Function and Structure in the Human Thalamus and Amygdala" [Grant-in-Aid], November 12, 1968-June 20, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 102)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology - Neuroscience Research Program, June 27, 1968-March 7, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 103)
  - McCrory, Wallace W. - "Developmental Nephrology" [Grant-in-Aid], July 12, 1967-October 9, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 104)
  - Menzel, Paul T. - "Costworthy Health Care? What Care? At What Cost? For Whom?", March 25, 1980-October 20, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 105)
  - Monroe, Russell R. - "Clinical Prediction and Tratment of Episodic Violence", June 24, 1976-April 18, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 106)
  - Mumford, Emily - "Interns, From Student to Physians" [Grant-in-Aid], October 21, 1965-July 31, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 107)
  - Mumford, Emily - "Interns, From Student to Physians" [Grant-in-Aid], October 21, 1965-July 31, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 108)
  - National Commission on Community Health Services - Drafts of Reports, October 8, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 109)
  - National Commission on Community Health Services - Drafts of Reports, October 8, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 110)
  - National Commission on Community Health Services - Publication of Reports, September 20, 1966-March 14, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 111)
  - Netsky, Martin G. - "Neurology: Teaching Neuropathology to the Undergraduate Medical Student", March 27, 1967-August 15, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 112)
  - Northwestern University (Medical School) - Honors Program in Medical Education, April 28, 1977-May 8, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 113)
  - Northwestern University (Medical School) - Honors Program in Medical Education, April 28, 1977-May 8, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 114)
  - Northwestern University (Medical School) - Honors Program in Medical Education, April 28, 1977-May 8, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 115)
  - Northwestern University (Medical School) - Honors Program in Medical Education, April 28, 1977-May 8, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 116)
  - Office of Population Research - "Population Index", September 4, 1977-May 25, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 117)
  - Office of Population Research - "Population Index", September 4, 1977-May 25, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 118)
  - Office of Population Research - "Population Index", September 4, 1977-May 25, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 119)
  - Paul, John - "History of the American Epidemiological Society", July 18, 1969-August 16, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 120)
  - Planned Parenthood-World Population - "Advanced in Planned Parenthood, Volume III", December 6, 1967-June 4, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 121)
  - Proger, Samuel - "Medical Education for Primary Care", August 20, 1974-February 17, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 122)
  - Proger, Samuel - "Medical Education for Primary Care", August 20, 1974-February 17, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 123)
  - Reader, George G. - "Hospital-Centered Medical Care", May 6, 1968-July 15, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 124)
  - Riccardi, Vincent - "The Genetic Approach to Human Disease", November 13, 1975-July 5, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 125)
  - Richards, Dickinson W. and Andre Cournand - "Physiology of Pulmonary Disorders", February 17, 1944-January 11, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 126)
  - Richards, Frederic M. - "Atlas of Blobular Protein Structures", March 5, 1969-January 27, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 127)
  - Richards, Frederic M. - "Atlas of Blobular Protein Structures", March 5, 1969-January 27, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 128)
  - Richards, Frederic M. - "Atlas of Blobular Protein Structures", March 5, 1969-January 27, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 129)
  - Richmond, Julius B. - "Currents in American Medicine", June 13, 1967-April 27, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 130)
  - Richter, Curt P. - "24 Hour Clock of Rats and Men", June 13, 1967-February 24, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 131)
  - Rosenfeld, Leonard - "Physician and Hospital Staff Distributions in Metropolitan New York" (Health and Hospital Planning Council of Southern New York), November 3, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 132)
  - Rosenfeld, Leonard - "Physician and Hospital Staff Distributions in Metropolitan New York" (Health and Hospital Planning Council of Southern New York), November 3, 1971-July 31, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 133)
  - Rosenfeld, Leonard - "Physician and Hospital Staff Distributions in Metropolitan New York" (Health and Hospital Planning Council of Southern New York), November 3, 1971-July 31, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 134)
  - Rubin, Ronald P. - "Calcium and the Secretory Process", September 25, 1972-July 6, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 135)
  - Sadler, Blair - Yale Trauma Program, January 16, 1970-February 28, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 136)
  - Scheinberg, I. Herbert - "Annotated Collection of the Major Papers of Dr. George Scatchard", July 7, 1971-July 28, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 137)
  - Schuknecht, Harold F. - "Otopathology", December 30, 1963-October 4, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 138)
  - Schuknecht, Harold F. - "Otopathology", December 30, 1963-October 4, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 139)
  - Senior, John R. - "Use of Computer Simulation" [Grant-in-Aid], May 22, 1974-March 25, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 140)
  - Senior, John R. - "Use of Computer Simulation" [Grant-in-Aid], May 22, 1974-March 25, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 141)
  - Senior, John R. - "Use of Computer Simulation" [Grant-in-Aid], May 22, 1974-March 25, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 142)
  - Senn, Milton J. E. - "The Milieu of the First Born" [Grant-in-Aid], May 8, 1966-September 13, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 143)